Abram Shook - Austin, Texas | 617-686-4263 | shookstack.atx@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Blog |

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Over 20 years of experience in multiple industries including tech, hospitality, training and music, with an eagerness to learn new skill sets and a focus on continuous improvement. Pursuing a career in software engineering at the intersection of creativity and programming. Adaptable problem solver with a calm, purposeful work ethic.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript - React - Ruby - Rails - AWS - HTML - CSS - Docker - Git - Bootstrap - Logic - ProTools - Ableton - Photoshop

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ATX Onstage - Website

Live music show-list and recommendation application for Austin area venues

The Song Sifter - Github | Demo

Musical idea generator for writing and arrangement, as well as fostering a sense of community amongst fellow artists.

- Built a complete full-stack unique project with Ruby/Rails backend and Javascript/React frontend
- Utilized authentication and authorization for secure user experience and deployed app via Heroku
- Leveraged Rails console, byebug, and Postman for testing, debugging, and troubleshooting
- Implemented filtering logic for users to search based on their preferred parameters

Beer Bites - Github | Demo

Web based app for suggestions on libations, food-pairings and local breweries

- Worked with Bootstrap component library for consistent layout and handled multiple API calls based on user inquiry
- Collaborated with pair-programming to divide the workload and deliver timely results using Github for organization
- Designed our schema layout and project functionality with Draw.io to showcase an MVP prior to writing any code

EXPERIENCE

Pushgig/ATXOnstage

Austin, TX

Software Engineer

8/2022 - present

- Building front-end features and custom search option with React
- Data aggregation and management for music-related sites using Node.js and Typescript
- Perform regular testing, debugging, troubleshooting on multiple API calls

 Accenture
 Austin, TX

 SME
 11/2020 - 04/2022

Recognized and reported complex user issues/bugs to the WhatsApp dev team

Pinpointed areas of improvement and implemented new guidelines to adhere to metrics and compliance regulations

Hai Hospitality
Trainer/Opening Captain

Austin, TX
02/2006 -10/2018

Lead a team of 40+ employees through trainings and standards of service with one-on-one reviews and mentorship

Communicated and facilitated changes between FOH, BOH, and management

 Apple
 Austin, TX

 Specialist
 01/2011 -01/2012

Kept up to date on all Apple products and services and helped first-time Mac users with personalized setup

EDUCATION

AWS Cloud Practitioner Austin, TX

Completed Amazon's certification program for AWS cloud fundamentals

02/2023

Flatiron School Austin, TX

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 04/2022 - 08/2022

Cabrillo College Santa Cruz, CA

music performance